Okay, so before we
get onto measurement, I
need to reset some
of your expectations and
make sure you're not
believing a lot of
the myths about how
growing a YouTube channel
and business works. So
let's start with the
first one. So remember
the story I told
you at the start
of the course where
I had spent months
making a video and
I posted it and
it got average views,
but then two weeks
later, boom, it went
parabolic. That's because YouTube
doesn't care about effort.
It's not emotional. It
just reacts to data.
And the data doesn't
always show instantly. It
has to test and
wait for the right
reaction before it pushes
it to more people.
So the myth I
want you to avoid
thinking about here is
that your videos have
to blow up the
second they're launched. It's
very, very rare videos
get pushed to a
new audience in the
first three days in
the way that people
expect. Myth number two.
So here's a video
I pulled 14 straight
days into, talking all
day, every day. I
gave this everything I
had. I posted and
it was a horrific
flop, but look. But
why did that happen?
Well, because in this
system I'm teaching you,
videos work as a
team. So when one
pops and finds the
right audience, YouTube's gonna
push your other stuff
at them. And because
of the way you
will have positioned your
channel around one problem
for one person, loads
of old videos can
live with it too.
So don't believe the
myth that old videos
are dead. That is
not true. Myth number
three. So in order
to get results on
YouTube and be able
to stand any chance
of competing against getting
views over all the
other channels your potential
viewers watch, you need
to get three of
these pillars above this
line. Until then, you
basically have to keep
practicing and not expect
much of a result.
Because you're just not
a standard that's able
to compete with other
people in your niche.
So let me break
down what these pillars
are. Pillar number one,
I can't really help
you with, but that's
basically how credible you
are and how much
expertise you have on
the topic. So if
you have a decade
of testimonials and frameworks
and success, you just
can talk about that
in your videos and
you'll stick out more
than anyone else. It's
a bit of a
cheat code. Now the
next pillar is about
how you communicate those
expertise. Okay, so you
know that you need
to make videos that
are new, easy, and
inspiring. And posting and
trying to get better
over time and sticking
to the plan I've
given you will get
this pillar higher, but
you need to understand
this is an art
that takes a lot
of practice, but don't
expect this to leap
up because you've watched
the course and made
two videos. The results
are in repetition, measurement,
and repeating what works.
And then we have
the presentation column. This
is basically how well
you come across on
camera. And most people
are 10 times worse
than they think they
are here. So if
you're not very engaging,
if you come across
as lacking confidence, or
you look like a
deer in the headlights
like this, where you're
reading the teleprompter and
you're shaking a bit,
your credibility is gonna
get wrecked. And that
will drop two columns
at once. We can't
have that. Again, don't
just expect to be
really good at presenting
after a few videos.
I'm still not that
great after thousands. And
then we have this
column, this is production.
So we need to
match our viewers' expectations
with the sort of
production quality they want.
But if you're shooting
on a webcam with
a messy background and
there's crap in the
background, why would anyone
listen to you? So
we need to make
sure this production quality
is above the line
too. So that was
the fourth pillar. You've
got to get three
of these above the
line. So you hit
a certain standard on
all of them, but
nailing everything I teach
you in this won't
work if this doesn't
happen. And it's why
most people fail. They
just don't realize they're
not good enough yet
to compete. So if
you're credible but new
to YouTube and you
have a nice studio,
your graph's gonna look
like this and you're
gonna have to really
level up to become
a master of communication
and presenting. Or this
is the chart from
my old channel, Film
Booth. I wasn't very
credible back then. I
didn't have many testimonials.
So I made up
for that by getting
as good as I
could at communicating, presenting,
and production. And this
would be my chart
now where suddenly I
had tons of credibility
and experience. So I
just dropped the production
quality because I don't
need to put as
much time and effort
in to keep people
watching to build that
trust and credibility. All
right, so myth number
four. Let's say half
a million people are
interested in your topic.
Getting 10 % of
those people to watch
a video is incredible.
That would be 50
,000 views. The thing
is, most people can't
get a 10 %
click -through rate. So
most niche creators in
this situation would max
out their average views
per video around 25K.
What this basically means
is you get to
a point where always
trying to get more
and more views kind
of wastes your time
and energy because you
cap out on your
niche ceiling. So what
you'd be better off
doing is turn around
and saying, do you
know what, I'm happy
at 25K views per
video. I'm not gonna
keep putting tons of
effort into YouTube or
try and push it.
Instead, I'm gonna focus
on the business and
optimize that more so
I can make more
money from those 25
,000 people. And that's
what this program is
gonna help you do.
But the myth there
to avoid is continuing
to be a niche
channel. So why is
it that you're continually
thinking you have to
keep beating your personal
best? At a certain
point, it's not possible
and you don't. That
brings us onto myth
number five. So why
does Russell Brunson, one
of the most famous
internet marketers of all
time, get hardly any
views on his YouTube
channel? He basically invented
funnels online, right? And
why do massive channels
with millions of subscribers
post low effort content
that brings back like
1 % of those
subscribers when there's smaller
channels out there getting
10 times their views?
Well, it's because they
already had their season
on YouTube and now
they do very little
to earn big money.
So they don't need
to put more effort
in. So let me
explain what that means.
So some of you
will have done this
with me. You might
have watched my videos
three years ago on
Film Booth, then disappeared
until a problem I
could maybe help you
with appeared in your
life. So you came
back to my channel
and watched a few
videos and went, I'm
just gonna pay Ed
to help. You didn't
come back because I
was viral. You came
back because I helped
you once many moons
ago and that value
stuck up here. So
the truth is, always
trying to get a
good video, trying to
be the top channel
in your niche is
dumb because if you
want to make this
work, you have to
build a business and
shift focus. And that
means eventually someone else
becomes the new breakout
thing because all they
do is make videos.
They don't have a
business. They can put
all their focus into
that. And this is
exactly what will happen
to those people if
they don't do what
I'm telling you. They'll
grow fast. They'll get
obsessed with maintaining their
views. They'll realize they
don't make enough money.
Then they'll burn out
and then they'll make
a video that says,
I don't enjoy this
anymore. I'm making content
for the algorithm, not
me. I want to
take some time off.
And then they'll take
the time off, post
their new video. And
then they'll go, oh
my gosh, the views
are awful doing what
I want. They'll have
another breakdown. And then
they'll go back to
doing exactly what they
were doing before. And
they'll always think to
themselves, this isn't worth
this. I can't make
any money. And eventually
they just quit. So
you don't need to
stay at the top.
At a certain point,
it's counterproductive. So your
goal should just be
to make great videos,
to build a fan
base, and then to
eventually maintain that fan
base who will come
with you for years
and then optimize your
sales and marketing so
you can actually earn
that. And the money
you deserve. I call
that the promised land.
There's no pressure. There's
no obsession with the
whole 10 out of
10 ranking. You just
have content that works,
a fan base and
an absolutely fantastic business
that grows. So knowing
that, let's move on
to the next video
where I'm going to
start to teach you
how to measure.